时间轴-Ice北极熊
翻译-遗落星痕 Ice北极熊
-Alright, we survived the crud -Yeah, we did
-终于，我们完成了 CRUD -是的，我们做到了
Create, read, update, delete
创建，读取，更新，删除
We are going to add in some logging, do a little Application Insights locally
接下来，我们将来添加日志功能，并在本地执行 Application Insights
and then in the process of doing logging, I also want to add a little thing called Temp Data
然后在记录日志的过程中，我还想添加一个名为 Temp Data 的小东西
Because I was noticing that when we did the create
因为我注意到，若在我们进行创建的时候
it'd be nice to have a little message that said the answer was created or whatever
能有一条消息表示正在创建或者其他提示，这样会更友好
Yeah, that would be nice.
嗯嗯，听起来不错
但这并不是模型的一部分，因此这会带来一些有趣的问题
But that's not really part of the model cuz that brings up some interesting questions
So, for example, if we go back to Create and just refamiliarize ourself with that, right?
例如，如果我们回到 Create 页面，对此我们都还有印象，是吧
We type in the name and we hit submit, and then if we look at the page model behind
我们输入名称，然后点击提交，在让我们看下相关的页面模型
that it's pretty straightforward, right?
一目了然，对吧
We have the customer that as you say with the BindProperty survives
我们有使用了 BindProperty 属性的用户，就像你说的
Survives the journey.
幸存的旅程
Survives the journey but it'd be nice to have a message that would be some temporary piece of data
幸存下来的旅程，但我们希望有一些像临时数据之类的
that would say, yeah customer got added
消息提示我们，用户添加成功了
So we could go and have a string and call it message.
所以我们可以添加一个字符串变量叫做 message
This is interesting though because it's part of the PageModel, but not part of the database.
这很有趣，因为它是页面模型的一部分，但不是数据库的一部分
This is part of the PageModel which is kinda like a view model.
这是页面模型的一部分，它有点像视图模型
This is really a temporary piece of data.
这实际上是一段临时的数据
It's Tempdata and they're gonna have their values stored and then they'll be right back around in the side.
这就是 Tempdata ，他们将在这储存相应的值，然后可以在另一个页面中访问
So it's a sidecar, it's a little post it note.
所以这就像是一个车斗，或者说是便利贴
That's a good way to think about those. Yeah.
这种思考问题的角度很不错。是的
Cool, so it's a place to put stuff.
很好，这就是一个放东西的地方
So I'm gonna save the database, save the data right here like we did before and then-
首先，我要保存数据库，就像我们之前那样保存数据，然后
You're gonna have a message.
你会收到一条消息
I'm gonna have a little message, and we'll say hey, Customer and this is where you can personalize stuff.
我将收到一些消息并提示，嘿，Customer ，在这里你可以自定义一些东西
-Customer.Name -added
-It's a message, right? -And it can come out of whatever you want
-这是一条消息，对吗？ -它可以来自你想要的任何东西
It can be generated, but here we're mixing and matching text with the data from the form.
它可以是生成的，而在这里我们将拼接文本与来自表单的数据
Then scrolling in a way in this message which is not part of the database.
然后回过头我们再来看下这个 message ， message 并不是数据库的一部分
So by simple fact that you had the TempData said, you're not going into the database.
所以，在这个简单的实例中，你使用的是 TempData ，而不必访问数据库
Right because I posted, well because I actually never picked it up and put it anywhere near the database.
是的，因为我提交了表单，而实际上我从来没有把它存到数据库的任何地方
If I did not put TempData on it, that would never get saved and it would be no
如果我没有在上面添加 TempData ，那它永远都不会保存下来，也不会
But because it's public and it's on the page model, it's available to me, you know, elsewhere, okay?
但是因为它是在页面模型上的 public 属性，所以我可以在其他地方使用它，对吗？
So let's go over to, let me think about this.
让我们回过头来，想一想
-Would you go to your index page? -Yeah, thank you
-是该到你的索引页面了吧？ -是的，谢谢
It took me a second to get my head right
我花了一秒钟让我的头脑清醒了一下
So on the index page, we're gonna go and make a message as well
所以在索引页面上，我们也会添加一条消息
That's gonna catch that temp data, right?
那会获得那些临时数据吧？
And then here, maybe we'll have some, we'll just take it at the top of the form for now and we'll say, maybe an H3.
然后在这里，也许我们需要一些，就把它放在表格的顶部，比如说是 H3 标签
-And some sort of message? -@Model.Message
-以及一些消息？ -@Model.Message
So it'd be or maybe we'd wanna hide it if it wasn't there
所以它将是这样，也许在消息不存在的时候
there is lots of things that we could could potentially do but for now
我们会想隐藏它，我们可以做很多的事情，但现在
Now, just a second, we'll be fine.
现在，只需一秒钟，我们这样就可以了
But this is just an example where it's not quite database stuff.
但这只是一个例子，它与数据库无关
You don't want to stick it in the database temporarily, you just want it to be somewhere temporarily
你并不想把数据临时保存到数据库中，仅仅是想找个地方临时保存下数据
Some sort of acknowledgement for the user
一些用户的操作信息
-Mm-hm, yep and the general idea of being able to, there you go -They are
-嗯，是的，这是一种常见的想法，这就可以了 -这些就是了
And that could look whatever you want it, you can do whatever.
这可以你想要的任意的东西，或者你想对它做任何操作都行
It could fade in with jQuery or animation, or whatever makes you happy.
它可以通过 jQuery 或动画添加淡入效果，或任何你喜欢的东西
-And that's different from there, which is your default state, right? -So do it again, See?
-（刷新后）这与刚才不同，这是默认状态，对吗 -让我们再来试一次，看到了吗
And it's because it was called temp data and we had the same name here and where it started
这是因为它被称为临时数据，我们在这里和它最初定义的地方有相同的名称
So it found its way magically over into the index area as well, which is pretty sweet
所以它就很神奇地来到了索引页面，多么贴心的功能啊
Now we talked a little bit about logging, very, very briefly
现在我们非常非常简短地来谈谈有关日志的事
-We didn't really do anything with it -Well we looked at this
-我们不会在日志中真正的做什么 -让我们来看下这个
-Well we saw it up here -We saw two different kinds of logging
-在这我们可以看到了 -我们看到了两种不同的日志记录
-We saw this one -And then we saw a little bit more there.
-我们看完了这个 -然后我们看到了更多信息
so there was warning, and then there was.
这些是警告的等级，然后这些是
Oops, pardon me.
哎呀，原谅我
It was, yeah there you go.
哦，这就是了
There's warning, and then there's debug and then you can have different subsections.
这里有警告，有调试，而且你可以有不同的小节
You can say, I just want information from Microsoft but I want debug from everyone else, right?
你可以说，我只想要来自微软的信息，但我希望得到其他人的调试信息，对吧？
So let's go see if we can figure out how to do logging.
那么我们来看看，我们是否可以弄清楚如何记录日志
All right, so we'll go back over to here, and I'm going to try to remember how to do this from scratch.
好的，我们回到了这里，我将尝试记住如何从头开始
Do you can you tell me how?
你能告诉我该怎么做嘛
You've gotta try to remember?
你要试着记住吗
Well, you know.
嗯，你懂得
I just want to do it right, and I don't have all this stuff in my head all the time.
我只是想做得对，而我一直没有把所有这些东西都放在脑海里
So it should be ILogger.
这里应该是 ILogger 吧
Is it, you probably need to add it as a service.
是的，但你可能需要添加相应的服务
Yes, add it as a service.
好的，添加服务
and then we have to use it.
我们必须使用它
Yeah, just AddLogging.
`AddLogging` 就好了
And then we've got app. I don't think it's used...
然后我们可以用 app ，我不认为它是这样用的
Do you put it up so, ILogger?
你把它搞定了吗，是 ILogger 吗
Yeah, I think it's ILoggerFactory.
我认为这应该是 ILoggerFactory
I think it's, yeah.
我想是的
-See? -Yes, you have to add the extension.
-看到了吗？ -是的，你必须添加扩展
Comes out of extensions, that's good.
这部分脱离出来变成了拓展，这很好
Geeks' work makes for the best work.
极客们的工作是它变得更好
Yeah, there you go, Okay.
那这样就好了
Then we'll say hey, loggerFactory, And you can say, well if I'm running it at the console, I can add the console.
然后我们只需这样，嘿， loggerFactory ，如果我在控制台中记录日志，我可以添加控制台
Cuz you can log to all kinds of places, right, you can log to files
而且你可以记录到各种各样的地方，比如说文件
you can log it into Application Insights if you will, all kinds of things
或者 Application Insights ，如果你愿意的话，各种东西都行
And if you go and do Application Insights that's going to ask you all kinds of questions as well.
如果你使用 Application Insights ，那它会需要一些参数
Right now for now, I'm going to AddConsole, I'm going to AddDebug.
现在，我就使用了 `AddConsole` 和 `AddDebug`
Do you need the first one any more?
你还需要第一行代码吗？
The console one is if I'm running it from the command line and if I ever want to, I'd think I'd like to have that
这行代码是在我从命令行运行的时候想要输出日志，那我想我会需要它
-So it's a choice? -Well it's a
-那么这是一个选择吗 -嗯，是的
I'm gonna be doing stuff or someone on my team works on the console and I'd like to be able to spit at them
若我或者我团队中的某人在控制台中运行时，我希望向他们输出些信息
To the console when possible
在有可能的情况下，向控制台输出
So what I'm trying to point out is that you don't need both of them, right?
所以我想说的是你不需要同时有两个，对吗
No, one, I'm pointing the I'm pointing the logging to multiple locations.
不不，在这我指的是我正在将日志输出到多个位置
I could point it out to app insights, I could put it in text file, I could put it in database.
我可以把它输出到 app insights ，文本文件，或者是数据库
It'd be weird,but I could do that
这很奇怪，但我能做到这一点
So right now I'm sending logging to two places, pardon me.
所以现在我把日志输出到了两个地方，原谅我
Yeah so yeah it's cool to do that and then, in a place that I might wanna use it
是的，这样做很酷，然后，在一个我可能想要使用它的地方
remember how we put everything on one line there before?
还记得我们之前如何把所有东西放在一行代码中嘛
We're gonna take it out and I think I would say, private ILogger.
我们要把它展开，我想我会用 private ILogger
And I think it would be of type CreateModel and I'll just say Log, and then we say ILogger Log
我认为它将是 CreateModel 类型，我只需键入 Log ，然后我们需要 ILogger log
and then again we squirrel it away
之后我们再次换行
Now here I am mixing things, here this person went underscore db, and I said capital L
现在这里我用了不同的风格，这里这个人使用的 _db ，我用的大写的 L
you should pick a style and stick with it
你应该选择一种风格并坚持下去
-So is the underscore really just a style? -It's just a style
-那么下划线真的只是一种风格吗？ -这只是一种风格
It's like saying this is private or it's read only, or it's internal.
就是说这是私有的，或者它是只读的，或是内部的
Lots of people have different styles.
很多人都有不同的风格
You tend to use capitals for publics.
公开属性最好以大写开头
There is a time when we used to say m_ for secret member.
曾经有一段时间我们使用 m_ 来标记私有成员
Now sometimes people put _ for internal, or read only.
现在人们有时把 _ 用于内部或只读变量
I'm just, I should be more responsible in the way I name my things.
我只想说我应该对我命名的方式更负责任
-Yes you should -I should
-是的，你应该的 -我会的
This string right here
这个字符串就在这里
I could maybe reuse And then, make it for log, okay?
我可以重用它，然后把它换成日志，对吗
-And I could say log -Level.
-我可以用 log -不同的日志等级
Yeah, I could say LogInformation, LogDebug, LogCritical.
是的，我可以用 LogInformation ， LogDebug ， LogCritical
Let's say, that that's critical It's totally not critical.
让我们用 critical 级别吧，虽然这完全不重要
But I could say, that's a bad thing.
但我可以说，这里出现了一些问题
My goodness, customer added.
客户也会说，我的天哪
Right and then, it might come out red, right?
对，然后，它可能会变红，对吧
And actually that would be cool to try.
实际上这值得我们去尝试一下
So, if I am a web application.
所以，如果是一个 Web 应用
-And where is my web application? -It is down here
-我的 Web 应用在哪里 -它在这儿
So let's go over to that location.
那么让我们去那个地方
And I'll try dotnet run in the command line.
我将尝试在命令行中执行 dotnet run
This is a good reminder that you can do these things in Visual Studio
这是一个很好的提醒，你可以在 Visual Studio 中做这些事情
or you can jump back out into the command line
或者你可以跳回命令行操作
-that's cool, too -So it's giving you 64005.
-这也很酷 -它给了你 64005端口
Oops, so I put that there, I put this here.
哦不，让我把它放在那里，把它放在这里
-There it was, critical -All right, that's the console one
-它在那， critical -很好，这是控制台的形式
So the idea there is that that information could go lots of different places.
之前提到过的想法，就是信息可以向多个不同的地方输出
-So let's close that up -We can see it in the debug
-所以让我们关闭它 -我们可以在调试中看到它
And and let's go and do it in Application Insights.
然后让我们在 Application Insights 中进行操作
And you can see the debugger as well, right?
你也可以看到调试器，对吗
The point is that, that stream of information is going out into the world
关键是，这条信息流正在向外传播
it can go out into the command line, it can go out into a window
它可以进入命令行，一个窗口
it can go into Windows Debug text file, totally up to you.
或是 Windows Debug 文本文件，这完全取决于你
All right, so, I'm gonna declare tab bankruptcy.
好吧，所以，我要关掉一下标签页
-This is too much, stressed me out Okay, go back over here
-这太多了，已经影响到我了 -好的，回到这里
And I'm gonna right-click, and I'm gonna say, Add > Application Insights
我要点击右键使用，添加 > Application Insights
-And you've done this before many times -Here's the trick, though
-而且你已经做过好几次了 -不过这是诀窍
You can do this and sign up in Azure, you can use it for free, you get like what, a gigabyte?
你可以这样做，注册一个 Azure 账号，你会发现这是免费的，大概会有 1G 的流量
-Something like that -There, we'll go and register your app
-就是这样 -在那里，我们将注册你的应用
And even though you're running your app locally, send the telemetry up into the cloud.
即使你在本地运行应用，也可以将遥测数据发送到云端
We'll do this a bit a little bit later.
我们稍后会这样做
But I wanna point out to people that you don't have to do it that way, okay?
但我希望向大家指出的是这并不是必须的，是吧
They would like you to sign up.
他们希望你注册
And l think that you would get value if you sign up.
而且我认为你注册是值得的
-But, you can also try local only -It's a little subtle.
-但是，你只尝试在本地运行也没问题的 -这也不错
So you can try local only which means none of your data would be sent up into the cloud.
因此，你可以尝试只在本地运行，这意味着你的数据不会被发送到云端
But it's a data that you can export and put somewhere else.
但你可以把这些数据导出来放到任意地方
Like, you can send a report to someone.
比如，你可以向某人发送报告
Sure, the point is that the cloud can give you a lot more insight, it's gonna apply all the analytics.
当然，重点是云可以为你提供更多洞察力，它可以提供所有的分析功能
And you have kinda an unlimited amount of space in the cloud.
而且你在云中拥有无限的空间
I think it's a gig for free.
我记得这些都是免费的
And then, beyond that, you can do all kinds of things in the cloud you can't do locally
然后，除此之外，你还可以在云中执行各种不能在本地执行的操作
But the point I'm making is that there's no reason not to try it out locally.
但我要说的是，没有理由不在本地尝试
You can do amazing stuff with it even on an airplane.
这样即使在没有网络的飞机上，你也可以用它做出惊奇的东西
-You know what I mean? -So, lets go and run this
-你知道我的意思吧 -所以，让我们去运行它
-And you just added the app inside some -Yeah, that's a good point
-你刚刚在一些应用内部添加了些什么 -嗯，问得好
By running that, I just added that package, and it plugged itself into the pipeline, okay?
通过执行前面的步骤，我添加了一个包，且它会将它自己添加到 pipeline 中
So you didn't have to manually add it into your pipeline at all.
因此，你不必手动将其添加到 pipeline 中
-It's automatically added by default? -Yeah, it's magic.
-它会默认自动添加 -是的，这很神奇
I think we can actually look at the, Let's go out to where that was
我想实际上我们可以看看它，让我们转到那里
Where is that file located?
这个文件在什么地方呢
The csproj is here, and we can open it up
csproj 在这里，我们可以打开它
-There it is -There, okay
-它就是了 -好的，好的
So it's just a package.
所以它只是一个包
And once it gets in there, it's plugged into the pipeline.
一旦它添加之后，就会添加到 pipeline
And it's gonna collect all kinds of stuff.
它会收集各种东西
But now I can go, and really query my application.
现在我可以去真正地查询我的应用
-So it's running right now -Should be clear
-它现在正在运行 -应该清理一下
Let's go and do our create stuff.
我们去创建一些内容
And I'll come in here, and I'll say look, see the numbers getting higher?
我会进入到这，注意看，这些数字正在逐渐增加
Let me do that again.
让我再来一遍
So add a new one.
添加一个新的东西
So these events are happening.
这些事件正在发生
So I can click on that, and this is what you wanna get.
我可以点击它，这就是你想要的
-This is sweet -I can see the number of requests, the number of traces
-这很贴心 -我可以看到请求以及跟踪的数量
You can filter it?
你可以对它进行过滤吗
Yeah, you can filter by, just show me creates, just show me people on this version, just show me people on Chrome
当然，你可以过滤，只是告诉我创建的信息，或是使用这个版本的人，或是使用 Chrome 的人
just show me people on Firefox, just show me things that took longer than a second, right?
或是使用 Firefox 的人，或是执行超过一秒的事情，对吧
You can go through this whole list here.
你可以在这里查看整个列表
And I could look for, look
我可以进行查找，看
And then it has this really good icons, so you know what's right, yeah.
然后它有这个非常友好的图标，让你你知道什么是对的
See, remember how we made adding a customer a critical.
看，还记得我们是怎样为添加客户添加一条 critical 日志的吗
So I can double-click on that individual trace, okay?
我还能双击这一条独立的追踪，对吧
So then, we can see the name of the computer and the operation.
那么，我们可以看到计算机的名称和操作
See, the severity, the operations.
看，这些是问题的严重程度和操作
And I can use, then show me all telemetry for this user.
我还可以这样做，显示这个用户的所有遥测数据
So then you could say, well, I've got a bunch of users hitting this.
你可以会有这样的情况，比如，我有一堆的用户触发了这个事件
This is where the local stuff will fall down at some point and then, you're gonna wanna go into the cloud.
在这一些有共同点的本地信息将会出现，然后你就知道云端的好处了
But one of the great options is, something's occurred.
但其中一个很好的选项是，当发送一些事时
Beyonce has been added.
Beyonce 已被添加
Show me telemetry five minutes before and after.
向我展示前后5分钟的遥测数据
All right, cuz the bug might not be near her, it might be around her.
对吧，因为 bug 可能不是她的问题，而是环境的问题
Around her, elsewhere on the elevator.
在她周围，或者更远的地方
Then, I can go and chart these things over time.
然后，我可以随着时间的推移去绘制这些东西
Again, this is all local.
同样，这都是本地的
This is the stuff you get locally.
这是你在当地获得的东西
And then when you wanna go beyond that, there's all kinds of great stuff in the Application Insights Portal.
然后，当你想要更多的信息时， Application Insights 门户中有各种各样的好东西
And this would link you, right?
这会帮你打开一个链接，对吧
Link you right there, and you can go and check it out.
链接就在那里，你可以去试一下
And we will explore a bunch of that stuff in another talk, see?
我们将在另一个谈话中探讨一堆这些东西，看这儿
Here, when you sign in, you can pick your resource and then, see dependencies
在这里，当你登录时，你可以选择你的资源，然后查看依赖项
how your application talks to the database, calls another web API
你的应用如何与数据库交互，调用另一个 Web API
Stuff you wouldn't be able to do if you didn't put it in the cloud
如果你没有把它放在云中，你就无法做到
And here I've just added a filter, and I've said Create
在这里，我刚刚添加了一个过滤器，我只选中了 Create 页面的数据
I can turn that filter off
我可以关闭那个过滤器
Just show me the longest ones
只展示花时最长的操作
Filter on those.
过滤掉那些
There's the record, there you go.
这些就是记录，你可以进一步查看
One of the requests took a long time, click on that.
其中一个请求花了很长时间，点击它
That was the initial get.
这是最初的请求
The very first time it compiled that page.
它第一次编译该页面
Isn't that fantastic?
这样是不是很棒
That is fantastic, that's pretty impressive.
这真是太棒了，令人印象深刻
I really like Application Insights.
我非常喜欢 Application Insights
Cool, so, I think that puts us in a pretty good spot, doesn't it?
很酷，所以，我觉得这让我们处于一个很好的观察视角，不是吗
We've got a nice little cloud application, basic Bootstrap, it's talking to Application Insights, we've got logging.
我们完成了一个不错的小型云应用，基本的 Bootstrap ，它正在与 Application Insights 交互，我们已经有了日志记录
I think that's a pretty good beginner start, wouldn't you say?
我认为这是一个非常好的初学者入门教程，你不觉得嘛
Yeah, we've accomplished quiet a bit over the past couple of hours.
是的，在过去的几个小时里，我们已经完成了很多的工作
Where should they go now?
那他们现在应该去哪
-The docs? -The docs, go to the docs.
-文档 -文档，去看文档吧
Go to docs.microsoft.com, get started.
转到 docs.microsoft.com ，开始吧
Great samples, great interactive experiences.
那有很棒的样例以及很棒的互动体验
And if you see this, send Hanselman an applause.
如果你看到了这里，请给 Hanselman 一个掌声
Yeah, say applause to us on Twitter.
是的，在推特上给予我们鼓励
On Twitter.
在 Twitter 上
Myself and Maria.
我和 Maria
And be sure to explore all the different great courses that are here at Microsoft Virtual Academy.
并且一定要浏览 Microsoft Virtual Academy 中的所有不同的优秀课程
This is just beginner ASP.NET Core.
这只是对于初学者的 ASP.NET Core 教程
We've got beginner C#, we've got all sorts of great cloud-based content, there's intermediate and advanced and on and on.
我们有面向初学者的 C＃ ，各种基于云的很棒的内容，以及中级和高级的内容等等
Thank you so much for spending your day with us here on Microsoft Virtual Academy.
非常感谢你在 Microsoft Virtual Academy 上与我们共度一天